

Leandro Rovagnoli

DATE OF BIRTH: 04/15/1989

CONTACT

Nationality: Brazilian



Porto, Portugal



leandro.rovagnoli@gmail.com



(+351) 913034495



https://leandrorovagnoli.dev

ABOUT ME

Bachelor degree in Information Systems, I have always considered myself a lover of technology and software development. Focused on the agile side, I have about 5 years of experience in web applications (.NET), software development & enhancement, and service delivery. I am always searching smarter ways to build applications that meet the needs of users in the best way possible.

COURSES ABROAD

11/2016 - 03/2019

Cultural Exchange in Australia

Cultural exchange with the aim of improving the English language and getting to know new cultures, having a significant development in the language since Elementary level (A1) to Upper Intermediate level (B2).

Courses held at Greenwich College and Discover English in Melbourne/ Australia for <u>one year</u>, and interacting 100% of the time with natives and students of other nationalities.

By the end of the language studies, I've also attended to a IT course (Diploma in Information Technology) for <u>one year and a half</u>, to improve the technical vocabulary and develop personal networking.

WORK EXPERIENCE

04/2020 - 04/2020 - Lisbon, Portugal

Web Developer

Saudade Flores Frescas (Lisbon)

- Freelance at commercial automation development
- Client belonging to the flower shop segment

Due to the pandemic moment, the flower shop was experiencing an increase of sales in an exponential way. Therefore, they weren't being able to answer all their customers.

Analysis the whole process involving all artefacts belonging to the company; Automation script in order to solve in a fast way the issue; Creation of templates for different situations for email purposes; Evolutionary maintenance as customer's request;

Techs: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Google Apps Script

10/13/2014 - 08/12/2016

Software Engineer

Resource IT Solutions

- Analysis and corrections project related to security in a client belonging to the financial / automobile industry;
- · Credit management project for vehicle approval and financing;

- The basis project was the implementation of specific security points detailed in some monthly reports that the client get us from Germany.

Analysis, execution and tests in the process of improving the security of systems belonging to the client. Corrections such as Input Validation, SQL Injection, Insecure Direct Objects References, Password and Handling were performed, among several situations where there was a lack in code integrity. Using specific points of Scrum / Kanban in a team of 9 developers, 22 different systems using since .NET platform up to classic ASP and VB6, Oracle, according to the development pattern of each system.

- Creation and evolutionary maintenance according to the customer's specification.

Techs: Scrum/Kanban, .NET $2.0 \sim 4.5$, C# and/or VB, ASP (classic), VB6, Oracle, SQL Server, TFS, Entity Framework, VB.NET, Visual Studio $2005 \sim 2015$, Javascript, HTML, Use of MainFrame by customer, according to the type of each system.

https://www.resourceit.com

02/25/2013 - 10/01/2014

.NET Developer

Norber

Company belonging to the Attendance Control / Timeclock System;
Creation and migration of a timeclock system, interpretation of punch in/out, implementation of intelligence to interpret various types of occurrences, among other specifics related to the business.

Techs: Scrum/Kanban, .NET MVC 4, NHibernate, C#, Linq, SQL Server 2008, Visual Studio 2013, Ajax, Jquery, TFS, TDD, Unit Test/Continuous Integration.

https://www.norber.com.br

01/25/2012 - 02/17/2013

Web Developer

4folhas

 Freelancer in the development of several projects as a Developer Analyst

Requirements, creation, maintenance and migration of systems for portals and simple websites, aiming to meet the needs of customers from different segments such as transportation, leisure, architecture, earthworks, lighting, among others.

Techs: ASP.NET 3.5/4.0, C#, SQL Server 2008, Mysql, Visual Studio 2010, Entity Framework, Ajax, Jquery, TortoiseSVN, Wordpress, SEO techniques, Linq to Entities.

08/05/2011 - 01/17/2012

ICT System Analyst

Stefanini

Client belonging to the credit protection branch;

Creation of a financial analysis system that manages the credit approval to companies.

Techs: ASP.NET 3.5, C#, SQL Server 2008, Visual Studio 2010, Ajax, Jquery, Unit Test, Use of MainFrame by the customer.

https://stefanini.com/

12/06/2010 - 07/07/2011

.NET Developer

Computeasy SA

Client belonging to the television industry;

Creation and evolutionary maintenance of an actors management system.

Techs: Microsoft Framework 4.0, ASP.NET, C#, Sql Server 2008, Visual Studio 2010, Ling, Jquery, Ajax, Entity Framework, CRUD, UML, SOLID.

10/13/2009 - 12/03/2010

Supervised internship as .NET Developer

Cyberlynxx SA (Tivit)

Client belonging to the health branch;

Creation of a medical report management system for an important hospital in the country, Hospital Albert Einstein. Development of the whole lifecycle since analysis, development, tests, deploy, homologation and post homologation.

Techs: Microsoft Framework 3.5, ASP.NET, C#, Sql Server 2005, Visual Studio 2008, Scrum/Kanban, Entity Framework, SOLID, Linq to Entities, CRUD, UML, Erwin (Data modeling and Reverse engineering), Ajax, Software testing, Exception Handling, Mnemonic Standard established by the client.

https://www.linkedin.com/company/cyberlynxx-s-a/

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

09/10/2019

ASP.NET Core: An e-Commerce with MVC and EF Core

Alura

https://www.alura.com.br

08/27/2019

ASP.NET Core: A webapp using the MVC standard

Alura

https://cursos.alura.com.br/course/introducao-ao-mvc-com-asp-net-core

08/22/2019

Entity Framework Core: Using the DataBase efficiently

Alura

https://cursos.alura.com.br/course/entity-framework-core

09/30/2013 - 10/11/2013

Web with ASP.NET MVC and persistence with NHibernate

Caelum Ensino e Inovação

https://www.caelum.com.br

08/06/2007 - 08/03/2011 - São Paulo

Bachelor in Information Systems

Universidade Paulista

EQF level 6 | http://unip.br

04/24/2010

 Core Web Application Technologies with Microsoft Visual Studio 2005

Ka Solution

https://www.kasolution.com.br

07/24/2009

Core Foundations of Microsoft .NET 2.0 Development

Ka Solution

https://www.kasolution.com.br

07/10/2009

 Introduction to Programming Microsoft .NET Applications with Microsoft Visual Studio 2005

Ka Solution

https://www.kasolution.com.br

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Portuguese

English

Listening **B2**

Reading C1

Spoken production **B2**

Spoken interaction **B2**

Writing **B2**